Practical Applications of the DFSS Methodology
Welcome back to this segment on Design for Six Sigma.
Let's start with a simple notion to understand
a little bit better about what we mean by Designing for Six Sigma.
Let's suppose for the sake of argument
that I have a little product here. I’m going to use a hardware example to start with.
We’ll say it's a radio. Represented by the box, a little antenna, and a radio wave there.
Now we know, that inside of here is circuits.
That operate that. We’ve all seen them with all the little lines going everywhere.
There's an electrical circuit. Now, I’m going to blow that
circuit up and show that as a circuit board.
And there's holes on there. And as we know,
for example a resistor, see there's like a resistor. There's the leads of the resistor.
Now, I'm not a hot artist, but you get the idea.
Going down through the hole and basically we come in here,
and we solder it right there, and we solder it right there.
So, that the electricity then can flow through that resistor
as it happily follows. It's what we call trace, on that circuit board.
Now, one element of that. For example, is related to this hole.
If I cross-section that hole, what I wind up with,
if I look at a cross-section through this board. Looking at it through here.
At that angle. There's the circuit board,
and there's a hole.
So, now we have that lead,
that kinda goes down through here like so, turns,
and there's the body of that resistor.
Now, I’m going to fill this in so we can get a little bit more of a better view of this.
Take just a second, but it will be worth it graphically here, to help us understand.
And I’ll make this kinda flow kinda solid like that.
And we’ll just make the resistor just
kinda like that. We can kinda begin to see what's going on there now. Huh?
Well, that's solder joint. Kinda comes in here like this and here
and here and here.
So, what we do is we put that solder on to lock that component
onto the circuit board. So, it don't move around and that ensures the electricity flows
through there, while maintaining it solid.
Now, if I could apply an upward force
to this. That's pull strength. So, imagine I got that and I’m pulling upward.
See. I'm trying to break the lead free of the circuit board.
So, I pull up on it and that's something that's called pull strength.
Pull strength. Very simple concept.
I've got a device, locate it, I pull it, and I measure how much force is required
to break that lead free of the solder connection.
Well, one of the things that we have.
When I do that. I'm going to make a scale here.
I'm going to make that as a vertical scale.
And I'm going to call that pull strength. Just pull for short.
Now along this axis, might be the solder joint temperature.
Temperature of the solder.
When the joint was made, and this is the corresponding pull strength.
Now what I do, is go out and make a bunch of solder joints, and I pull them and test them.
So, I’ve recorded, here’s circuit board 1.
Board number 1, 2, 3, 4.
Here's the pull strength. Whatever that may be, right there.
And there's the temperature for that board when it was made.
See, that's the corresponding temperature. So, there's the temperature.
And there's the scale of the pull strength for each board.
And I simply now locate it. I find the temperature
and the corresponding pull strength, and I make a dot.
Now, I do that for all my circuit boards.
That’s the way it kinda winds up.
Of course, this is called a scatter diagram.
It shows the correlation between temperature and pull strength.
Now, at a certain point it’s going to get so hot out here.
It's gonna start to roll back over again and come back down.
Well we’re going to ignore that for right now.
And what I’m going to do is put in here, an upper limit
and I'm going to put in here a lower limit. Just kinda like that. That bands that relationship.
So, if I know that the minimum pull strength expectation is right here.
Minimum pull strength. That's what the customer wants. That's the customer standard.
The minimum accepted pull strength is right there.
Then given that minimum. I also might have a maximum.
That the customer wants. So, I project top to top.
Bottom to bottom, project down,
and that's the range of temperature that I have to hold to ensure
the pull strength is between those limits.
So, what I'm doing is setting specifications.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.